Lindley Family collection, 1892-1944 C118
Indiana University Archives
Lindley Family collection
1892-1944
Indiana University Archives
Lindley family
C118
1.6 cubic feet
The Lindley Family collection is comprised of the papers of Ernest H. Lindley, Elizabeth Kidder Lindley, and Ernest K. Lindley. Ernest H. Lindley was a graduate of Indiana University, a professor of Philosophy at IU, the President of the University of Idaho, and the Chancellor of the University of Kansas. His wife Elizabeth Kidder Lindley was an 1893 graduate of Indiana University. Their son Ernest K. Lindley was a noted political writer and commentator. This collection consists of correspondence received by family members, the writings of Ernest H. Lindley, newspaper clippings, and personal materials.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.
Biographical Note
Dr. Ernest Hiram Lindley was born October 2, 1869, to Hiram and Laura White Lindley in Paoli, Indiana. Lindley attended Indiana University where he received his Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy in 1893 and his Master of Arts in Philosophy in 1894. He received a Ph.D. from Clark University in 1897.
After graduating with his bachelor's degree, Lindley was appointed instructor in Philosophy at Indiana University. He served as an Instructor in Philosophy at Indiana University from 1893-1897, as Assistant Professor from 1897-1898, as Associate Professor in Psychology (Department of Philosophy), 1898-1902, and as Psychology Professor and Head of Philosophy, 1902-1917. From 1917-1920, Lindley was President of the University of Idaho in Moscow, ID. He went on to become the Chancellor of the University of Kansas from 1920-1939. Lindley retired in 1939 and went on a tour of the Orient to study educational institutions.
Dr. Lindley was an accomplished author and researcher. He belonged to the American Psychological Association, Religious Education Association, Western Philosophical Association, Sigma Xi, Phi Beta Kappa, Sigma Chi. The Science Hall on IU's campus was renamed Lindley Hall after Ernest H. Lindley in 1957.
Lindley married Elizabeth Kidder on September 18, 1895. They had two sons, Ernest Kidder Lindley and Stanley Bryan Lindley. Lindley died on August 21, 1940 while enroute to San Francisco from Japan on August and was buried at sea.
Elizabeth Kidder Lindley was born on January 10, 1870, in Richmond, Indiana to Peter and Emily Kidder. She attended Earlham College in Richmond, Indiana from 1891-92 before coming to Indiana University. Lindley graduated from Indiana University in 1893 with a Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy. She married Ernest H. Lindley on September 18, 1895. They had a son Ernest Kidder Lindley in 1899 and another son Stanley Bryan Lindley in 1906. Alumni directories from Earlham College indicate Lindley was involved in woman suffrage work. She was traveling with her husband when he died. Lindley returned to Lawrence, Kansas where they had lived since 1920. She died in 1944.
Ernest Kidder Lindley was born on July 14, 1899, in Richmond, Indiana. Lindley first attended Indiana University where he was a member of Phi Kappa Psi, The Indiana Union, and The Garrick Club. He later attended the University of Idaho where he served as Editor-in-chief of the student newspaper and graduated in 1920. Lindley served in the Army during World War I. After graduating from college, he was awarded a Rhodes Scholarship and spent three years studying at Oxford University in England.
In 1924, Lindley joined the staff of The New York World as a reporter and political writer. He next worked at the New York Herald Tribune from 1931-1937. In 1937, Lindley became the Washington bureau chief of Newsweek and worked for the magazine until 1961. From 1938-1943, he worked for the Washington Post as a reporter and columnist. In 1961, Lindley became a special assistant to Secretary of State Dean Rusk and a member of the State Department's Policy Planning Council. He worked for the State Department until 1969. Additionally, Lindley worked as a commentator on network radio and television programs, a writer for various national magazines, and a lecturer on international affairs.
Lindley wrote the first book about Franklin Roosevelt and authored several books related to Roosevelt and his policies. He was the winner of many journalistic awards and had several honorary degrees. In 1974, Lindley was elected a scholar by the Distinguished Alumni Service Award Club of Indiana University.
On October 5, 1929, Lindley married Helen Elizabeth "Betty" Grimes. They had three sons, Jonathan, Christopher, and Mark. The couple were married until her death in 1976. At the time of his death, Lindley was married to Jean Gehman Lindley. He died on June 30, 1979 of cancer.
Arrangement
Organized in three series: Ernest H. Lindley, Elisabeth Kidder Lindley, and Ernest K. Lindley.
Scope and Content Note
Series: Ernest H. Lindley 1892-1940.
Subseries: Correspondence 1917-1940, is by no means all of Dr. Lindley's correspondence. This collection only offers a few letters regarding his professional career, but his personal correspondence offers an abundance of letters from Dr. and Mrs. William Lowe Bryan (1917-1939), from the Carnegie Foundation (1934- 1939) and William T. Foster(1920-1939).
Subseries: Writings, 1893-1939. This subseries is further separated into four subseries: Academic Career, Publications, Speeches, and Notes.
Subseries: Academic Career, 1893-1925, offers a sampling of Lindley's undergraduate work including his thesis, doctoral dissertation and some of his post doctoral research.
Subseries: Academic Publications 1897-1938, is not an exhaustive list, most of these publications were produced during his time at the University of Kansas 1920-1939; however, there are some publications during his time at Indiana University and Iowa.
Subseries: Speeches, 1899-1939, contains some of his speeches and presentations given throughout his career. Also included are some unidentified or incomplete speeches.
Subseries: Notes, 1894, n.d., contains notes taken during a lecture given by Dr. W. L. Bryan as well as personal notes and two personal notebooks.
Subseries: Biographical, 1890-1941, includes biographical information about Dr. Lindley and is organized in three subseries: General, Trip to China, and Death of E.H. Lindley.
Subseries: General, 1890-1941, n.d., primarily consists of newspaper articles from his professional career at IU, the universities of Idaho and Kansas, and some biographical information.
Subseries: China trip, 1939-40, includes mostly souvenirs and pamphlets of places he and his wife visited.
Subseries: Death of E.H. Lindley, 1940-41, n.d., mainly consists of memoriams and newspaper clippings concerning his death.
Series: Mrs. Elisabeth Kidder Lindley 1892-1944.
Subseries: Correspondence 1920-1941, includes subseries of Mother's Death, 1920 and Death of Dr. Lindley, 1940-41, n.d. Prominent correspondents include: Mrs. Charlotte Lowe Bryan, Alice and Frank Dains, Harrison C. Dale, Lucy Calhoun, Charles and Anna Jenkins, Walter and Eleanor Jessup, Raymond Nichols, D. M. Swarthout and Herman B Wells.
Subseries: Biographical 1892-1944, includes a letter of reference, and newspaper clippings and other materials concerning her death.
Series: Correspondence of Ernest K. Lindley 1941-56, includes some correspondence that he received after the death of his father in 1940, but most of it is after the death of his mother 1944. Prominent correspondents include Dr. and Mrs. William Lowe Bryan and Herman B Wells.
Separated Material
Photographs moved to photo files under "Lindley, Ernest Hiram - Accn. 0891"
Acquisition Information
Accession 0891
Lindley, Ernest Kidder, 1899- -- Archives; Lindley, Elisabeth Kidder, 1870-1944 -- Archives; Bryan, William Lowe, 1860-1955 -- Correspondence; Wells, Herman B -- Correspondence; Wells, Herman B -- Correspondence -- Selections; Bryan, Charlotte Lowe, 1867-1948 -- Correspondence; Bryan, William Lowe, 1860-1955 -- Correspondence -- Selections; Lindley, Ernest Hiram, 1869-1940 -- Archives; Lindley, Ernest Hiram, 1869-1940 -- Correspondence; Lindley, Ernest Hiram, 1869-1940 -- Correspondence -- Selections; Lindley, Ernest Kidder, 1899- -- Correspondence; Lindley, Ernest Kidder, 1899- -- Correspondence -- Selections; Lindley, Elisabeth Kidder, 1870-1944 -- Correspondence; Lindley, Elisabeth Kidder, 1870-1944 -- Correspondence -- Selections; Bryan, Charlotte Lowe, 1867-1948 -- Correspondence -- Selections
- Ernest H. Lindley, 1892-1940
  - Subseries: Correspondence, 1917-1940
    - "A" (General), 1920-1940 (Box 1)
    - "B" (General), 1920- (Box 1)
    - Binford, Mrs. A.O., 1932 (Box 1)
    - Bryan, E.A., 1920-1921 (Box 1)
    - Bryan, E.B., 1920-21 (Box 1)
    - Bryan, William Lowe, 1917-1939 (Box 1)
    - Butler, A.D., 1920-1921 (Box 1)
    - "C" (General), 1920-1921 (Box 1)
    - Carnegie Foundation, 1934-1939 (Box 1)
    - Cravens, John W., 1920 (Box 1)
    - "D" (General), 1919 (Box 1)
    - Eigenmann, C.H., 1917-1920 (Box 1)
    - "F" (General), 1920 (Box 1)
    - Foster, William T., 1920-1938 (Box 1)
    - French, Burton L., 1920 (Box 1)
    - "G" (General), n.d. (Box 1)
    - "H" (General), 1921-1940 (Box 1)
    - Hadley, Hiram, 1919-1921 (Box 1)
    - Holland, E.O., 1920-1940 (Box 1)
    - Jessup, W.A., 1920 (Box 1)
    - Jordan, David Starr, 25 May 1925 (Box 1)
    - "K" (General), 1920-1930 (Box 1)
    - "L" (General), 1920-1940 (Box 1)
    - Lawson, Paul B., 1939-1940 (Box 1)
    - Lindsey Family (General), 1917-1936 (Box 1)
    - Lindley, Grace, 1923 (Box 1)
    - "M" (General), 1917- (Box 1)
    - Miller, George Morey, 1920- (Box 1)
    - Miller, John A., 1920 (Box 1)
    - Moore, Henrietta E., 1920 (Box 1)
    - "N" (General), 1920 (Box 1)
    - Nichols, Raymond, 1939-1940 (Box 1)
    - "P" (General), 1920 (Box 1)
    - Parsons, L.F., 1920 (Box 1)
    - Preston, Katherine, 1938 (Box 1)
    - "R" (General), 1917-1920 (Box 1)
    - Reed, Florence, 1920-1921 (Box 1)
    - "S" (General), 1939 (Box 1)
    - Stempel, Guido H., 1917-1920 (Box 1)
    - Stockton, Margaret S., 14 Apr 1939 (Box 1)
    - Sutton, Dr. and Mrs. Richard L., 1937-1940 (Box 1)
    - Swarthout, D.M., 1939-1940 (Box 1)
    - Terman, L.M., n.d. (Box 1)
    - "W" (General), 1920-1936 (Box 1)
    - General., n.d (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Envelopes, Fragments, etc., n.d. (Box 1)
  - Writings, 1893-1939; n.d.
    - Academic Career, 1893-1925; n.d.
      - "God as Will", Before 1893 (Box 1)
      - "A Method of Studying Dermal Sensibility", 1893 (Box 1)
      - "Do Oratorical Contests Pay?", c. 1893 (Box 1)
      - "Euphony", c. 1893 (Box 1)
      - "The Plant of the Central Stone Company", c. 1893 (Box 1)
      - "A Review of Roy the Royalist", c. 1893 (Box 1)
      - "A Visit to Hampton Roads", c. 1893 (Box 1)
      - "An Experiment in Advertising Research", Before 1916 (Box 1)
      - Draft of Resolutions for the Association of State Universities, 1925 (Box 1)
      - Brain Charts (Post-Doctoral Work, Germany), n.d. (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous Drafts, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Publications, 1897-1938
      - A Study of Puzzles (Doctoral Dissertation at Clark University), 1897 (Box 1)
      - "Ueber Arbeit und Ruhe", 1900 (Box 1)
      - "Mental Hygiene: Retrospect and Prospect", 1916 (Box 1)
      - "An Experience with Anaesthetics", Before 1917 (Box 1)
      - Announcement and Memoriam, 1919 (Box 1)
      - "The University and the Vocations of Men", After 1920 (Box 1)
      - "Why Stop Learning?", After 1920 (Box 1)
      - "From the Chancellor" (in Graduate Magazine), Nov 1920 (Box 1)
      - "Education: A World Underwriter", 1923 (Box 1)
      - "The Universities and the People", 1925 (Box 1)
      - "Founding Vision and the Course of the University", 1938 (Box 1)
      - "Lotus Delta Coffman--An Interpretation", 1938 (Box 1)
    - Speeches, 1899-1939; n.d.
      - "A New Arithmetical Prodigy with Demonstration" (Given with W.L. Bryan), 27 Dec 1899 (Box 1)
      - "Being Good", Before 1917 (Box 1)
      - List of Speeches for Speeches for "Sunday Afternoons in the Reed College Chapel", Feb-Jun 1917 (Box 1)
      - Touring Lecture Series, 1917 (Box 1)
      - "The Control of Educational Institutions", 12 Jul 1928 (Box 1)
      - "The New Frontier: Charge to the Class of 1932" (Box 1)
      - "Hands and Wings", 1936 (Box 1)
      - Commencement, 1939 (Box 1)
      - "Art and the World of Men" (Box 1)
      - Unidentified and Incomplete Writing or Speech (Box 1)
    - Notes, 1894; n.d.
      - Lecture by Dr. W.L. Bryan, 1894 (Box 1)
      - George Washington / Revival of Personality, n.d. (Box 1)
      - Notebook, n.d. (Box 1)
      - Personalized Notepad, n.d. (Box 1)
      - Unidentified Notes, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Biographical, 1890-1941; n.d.
    - General, 1890-1941; n.d.
      - 18th Biennial Convention of the Sigma Chi Fraternity, 28 Nov 1890 (Box 1)
      - Commencement (IU Bloomington), 1893 (Box 1)
      - Outline of "Experimental Psychology" course taught by Lindley (Clark University), 1896 (Box 1)
      - Newspaper Clippings (Indiana University), 1900-1917 (Box 1)
      - Outline of "General Psychology" course taught by Lindley (Clark University), 15-27 Jul 1901 (Box 1)
      - 38th Annual Session of the Southern Indiana Teachers' Association (Speech Program), 27 Mar 1914 (Box 1)
      - Bloomington High School Commencement (Program), 29 May 1914 (Box 1)
      - The State College of Washington Commencement (Program), 6-11 Jun 1914 (Box 1)
      - Newspaper Clippings (Idaho University), 1917-1920 (Box 1)
      - Newspaper Clippings (University of Kansas), 1920-1939 (Box 1)
      - "What Editors Think of Lindley" (Graduate Magazine), Nov 1920 (Box 1)
      - "Concerning Dr. and Mrs. Lindley" (Graduate Magazine), Jan 1921 (Box 1)
      - Inauguration at the University of Kansas, 7 Jun 1921 (Box 1)
      - Guestbook of Dr. and Mrs. E.H. Lindley, 1921-1939 (Box 1)
      - "The Memorial and KU's New Day" by, Thornton Cooke in The University of Kansas News Letter, 10 Apr 1922 (Box 1)
      - Dedication to E.H. Lindley in The University of Kansas Alumni Association of Kansas City Roster, 1922-1923 (Box 1)
      - Graduate Magazine, Jan 1925 (Box 1)
      - "Kulture and Kansas: The Emancipated University of the Free State" by, George Marvin, in The Outlook, 7 Apr 1926 (Box 1)
      - The Gridiron Club of Washington, DC April Dinner, 13 Apr 1929 (Box 1)
      - Certificate for Associate Membership in the American Museum of Natural History, 31 Dec 1934 (Box 1)
      - Convocation in Recognition of 15 years of service, 11 Feb 1936 (Box 1)
      - "Rods Go Fast When Tarpon Leap" by, Dr. Richard L. Sutton, in Outdoor Life, Jan 1937 (Box 1)
      - University of Kansas Newsletter (picture, inside cover), 1 May 1937 (Box 1)
      - Graduate Magazine (picture, p.4), Sep 1937 (Box 1)
      - Announcement of his Retirement in Graduate Magazine, Dec 1938 (Box 1)
      - "Lindleys Retire in Greatest Goodwill", Graduate Magazine, Jun 1939 (Box 1)
      - Commencement, 9-12 Jun 1939 (Box 1)
      - "President's Letter", Graduate Magazine, 1939-1941 (Box 1)
      - "Profile of a Prexy" by, Henry Van Brunt, in The Magazine of Sigma Chi, Oct 1940 (Box 1)
      - Corner Stone Ceremonies, Lindley Hall (Univ. of Kansas) 1, Jun 1942 (Box 1)
      - "Dr. Lindley's Christmas Present" by, F.D. Farrell, Spring 1956 (Box 1)
      - "The Hectic Birth of the Board of Regents" by, Fred Ellsworth, Jan/Feb 1964 (Box 1)
      - Unidentified Menu for Sigma Chi Banquet, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Trip to China, 1939-1940
      - Miscellaneous Brochures, 1939-1940 (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous Notes, 1939-1940 (Box 1)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1939-1940 (Box 1)
      - Trip to Yenching University, 1940 (Box 1)
    - Death of E.H. Lindley, 1940-1941
      - Memorial Service, 22 Aug 1940 (Box 1)
      - Walter A. Jessup, 13 Sep 1940 (Box 1)
      - Memorial Services (Indiana University), 13 Oct 1940 (Box 1)
      - Musical Memorial, 17 Nov 1940 (Box 1)
      - "Thirty-Eighth Biennial Report of the Chancellor", 15 Dec 1940 (Box 1)
      - List of Letters received after Dr. Lindley's death, 1940 (Box 1)
      - Commemoration of E.H. Lindley (Univ. of Kansas), 1940 (Box 1)
      - Biographical Essays, 1940; n.d. (Box 1)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1940-1941 (Box 1)
      - Charl Ormond Williams, 28 Jan 1941 (Box 1)
      - Commemorative Service (Univ. of Kansas), 8 Jun 1941 (Box 1)
      - Unidentified Commemoration, (c.1940) (Box 1)
      - List of Committee for E.H. Lindley Memorial Lectureship (Box 1)
      - Memorium, William Lowe Bryan, n.d. (Box 1)
      - Memorium, Walter A. Jessup (Carnegie Foundation). (Box 1)
- Mrs. Elisabeth Kidder Lindley, 1892-1944
  - Correspondence, 1920-1941
    - Mother's Death, 1920
      - "A" (General), Oct 1920 (Box 1)
      - "B" (General), Oct 1920 (Box 1)
      - Bryan, Charlotte Lowe 5,7 Oct 1920, 5 Oct 1920 (Box 1)
      - Faculty, University (General), Oct 1920 (Box 1)
      - "H" (General), Oct 1920 (Box 1)
      - Iddings, Maud, 13-22 Oct 1920 (Box 1)
      - "K" (General), Oct 1920 (Box 1)
      - "L" (General), Oct 1920 (Box 1)
      - "P" (General), 6-7 Oct 1920 (Box 1)
      - "R" (General), Oct-Nov 1920 (Box 1)
      - "S" (General), Oct 1920 (Box 1)
      - "T" (General), Oct 1920 (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous, Sep-Nov 1920 (Box 1)
    - Death of Dr. Lindley, 1940-1941
      - "A" (General), Aug 1940-Feb 1941 (Box 1)
      - Anna (sister), 21 Aug-14 Sep 1940 (Box 1)
      - Ashton, Cora, 21 Aug. 1940; 23 Aug 1940 (Box 1)
      - "B" (General), Aug-Dec 1940; n.d. (Box 1)
      - Binford, Mrs. A.O., (1940) (Box 1)
      - Bohannon, E.W., 1921; n.d. (Box 1)
      - Brandenburg, W.A. and Alta, 5 Sep 1940 (Box 1)
      - Bryan, Dr. and Mrs. William Lowe, Aug 1940-Jan 1941 (Box 1)
      - Burnett, Nellie F., 23 Aug 1940; n.d. (Box 1)
      - "C" (General), Aug 1940-Jan 1941 (Box 1)
      - Calhoun, Lucy, Aug-Oct 1940 (Box 1)
      - Carnegie Foundation, 1940-1941 (Box 1)
      - Coffman, Mary F., Aug-Sep 1940 (Box 1)
      - Cooke, Thorton and Emily Darlington, Aug-Oct 1940 (Box 1)
      - "D" (General), Sep-Nov 1940; n.d. (Box 1)
      - Dains, Alice and Frank, Aug 1940-Jan 1941 (Box 1)
      - Dale, Harrison C., Aug 1940-Feb 1941 (Box 1)
      - Deputy, M., 19 Dec 1940-26 Jan 1941 (Box 1)
      - Doolittle, Dudley, 14 Oct 1940 (Box 1)
      - "E" (General), Aug-Sep 1940; n.d. (Box 2)
      - "F" (General), Aug-Nov 1940 (Box 2)
      - Faculty Womens' Club, 17 Sep 1940; 15 Oct 1940 (Box 2)
      - Ferguson, Mary and John, Aug 1940-Mar 1941 (Box 2)
      - Foster, Mrs. William M., 6 Dec 1940 (Box 2)
      - Frazier, Sally and Chester, Jul 1940-Mar 1941 (Box 2)
      - "G" (General), Aug-Nov 1940; n.d. (Box 2)
      - Geltch, Waldemar, 26 Aug 1940; 24 Sep 1940 (Box 2)
      - Gould, Nellie, 3 Jan 1941; 17 Jan 1941 (Box 2)
      - "H" (General), Aug 1940-Jan 1941; n.d. (Box 2)
      - Haggart, Laura., 22 Aug 1940; n.d. (Box 2)
      - Haggerty, Mrs. Laura, 1940-1944 (Box 2)
      - Haskell, Agnes and Henry, 21 Aug 1940; 18 Sep 1940 (Box 2)
      - Haus, Aurel and S. Herbert, 12 Sep 1940; 3 Feb 1941 (Box 2)
      - Hershey, L. Susanne, 14 Aug 1939; 7 Sep 1940 (Box 2)
      - Holland, E.O., 1940-1941 (Box 2)
      - Holland, Margaret (Box 2)
      - Houghton, Carol C., 5 Aug 1940; 29 Nov 1940 (Box 2)
      - Huggins, Alice Margaret, 2 Aug 1940; n.d. (Box 2)
      - Huggins, Mabel I., 4 Aug 1940; 25 Aug 1940 (Box 2)
      - "I" (General), Aug-Dec 1940 (Box 2)
      - "J" (General), Aug-Sep 1940; n.d. (Box 2)
      - Jenkins, Charles Anna, 3 Sep 1940; 24 Jan 1941 (Box 2)
      - Jessup, Walter and Eleanor, Aug 1940-Jan 1941 (Box 2)
      - "K" (General), Aug 1940-Jan 1941 (Box 2)
      - Kappa Alpha Theta, 2 Sep 1940; 3 Sep 1940 (Box 2)
      - "L" (General), Aug 1940-Jun 1941 (Box 2)
      - Lindley, Grace, 12 Sep 1940; 14 Oct 1940 (Box 2)
      - Lindley, Ernest (son), 22 Aug 1940 (Box 2)
      - Lindley, Stan and Jean, 19 Jul 1940; 6 Aug 1940; 21 Aug 1940 (Box 2)
      - "M" (General), Jul 1939-Oct 1940; n.d. (Box 2)
      - Major, Ralph and Margaret, 22 Aug 1940 (Box 2)
      - Malott, Deane, 1940-1942 (Box 2)
      - Miller, Marie, 7 Sep 1940 (Box 2)
      - Moreau, F.J., Aug 1939-Aug 1940 (Box 2)
      - "N" (General), n.d. (Box 2)
      - Nichols, Raymond, Aug 1940-May 1941 (Box 2)
      - "O" (General), Sep 1940; n.d. (Box 2)
      - O'Leary, Matilda H., 22 Aug 1940; n.d. (Box 2)
      - "P" (General), Aug 1940-Jan 1941; n.d. (Box 2)
      - Peiping Union Medical College, 18-23 Jul 1940 (Box 2)
      - Preston, Katherine, 5 Sep 1940; 5 Jan 1941 (Box 2)
      - "R" (General), Aug 1940-Dec 1940; n.d. (Box 2)
      - Regester, Mr. and Mrs. J. Frank (Box 2)
      - Roberts, Roy, Aug-Sep 1940; n.d. (Box 2)
      - Rupp, Elizabeth, 4 Sep 1940; n.d. (Box 2)
      - "S" (General), Aug-Dec 1940; n.d. (Box 2)
      - Simons, Gertrude R., 16 Sep 1940; 6 Dec 1940 (Box 2)
      - Sissin, Ehrin N., 5 Sep (1940); n.d. (Box 2)
      - Smyth, Robert and Jane, Jul 1940-Jul 1941 (Box 2)
      - Snow, Edith Huntington, 29 Aug 1940; 22 Feb 1941 (Box 2)
      - Stempel, Myrtle E. and Guido H., Sep 1940-Mar 1941 (Box 2)
      - Stouffer, Ellis and Anna, 21 Aug 1940; 29 Aug 1940 (Box 2)
      - Stuart, T. Leighton, 21 Aug 1940; 23 Aug 1940 (Box 2)
      - Sutherland, May, Aug 1940-Jan 1941 (Box 2)
      - Sutton, Richard, Aug-Dec 1940 (Box 2)
      - Swarthout, D.M., 14 Nov 1940; 8 Apr 1941 (Box 2)
      - "T" (General), Aug-Oct 1940 (Box 2)
      - Teter, Nellie Showers, 1936 (Box 2)
      - Tom, Mabel E., 27 Sep 1940; 22 Nov 1940 (Box 2)
      - "U" (General), 8 Nov 1940 (Box 2)
      - "V" (General), Aug-Sep (1940) (Box 2)
      - "W" (General), Aug-Oct 1940; n.d. (Box 2)
      - Wahl, H.R., Sep-Dec 1940 (Box 2)
      - Wei, D.K., 14 Aug 1940; 10 Oct 1940 (Box 2)
      - Wells, Herman B., 1940 (Box 2)
      - Werner, Henry and Ellie, 29 Aug 1940; 14 Oct 1940 (Box 2)
      - White, W.A., Oct 1940 (Box 2)
      - Wigmore, Harry and Emma, 4 Feb 1941 (Box 2)
      - Wilson, Robert and Marjorie, 4 Sep 1940; 12 Feb 1941 (Box 2)
      - Wilbur, Roy Lyman, Aug 1940-Feb 1941 (Box 2)
      - "Y" (General), 25 Sep 1940 (Box 2)
      - Ziegler, Lloyd and Grace, Aug 1940-Jan 1941 (Box 3)
      - Misc. Envelopes, Letter Fragments & Cards, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Biographical, 1892-1944
    - Letter of Reference, 15 Jul 1892 (Box 3)
    - Memorial Service, 7 Feb 1944 (Box 3)
    - Newspaper Clippings concerning the death of Mrs. E.H. Lindley, 1944 (Box 3)
    - List of Contributors to the Flower Fund in Honor of Mrs. E.H. Lindley, (c.1944) (Box 3)
- Correspondence of Ernest K. Lindley, 1941-1956
  - "A" (General), Feb 1944 (Box 3)
  - "B" (General), 14 Feb-12 Mar 1944 (Box 3)
  - Boynton, Flora, 6 Feb-6 Mar 1944 (Box 3)
  - Bryan, Dr. and Mrs. William Lowe, 6-13 Feb 1944 (Box 3)
  - "C" (General), 10 Feb-15 Mar 1944 (Box 3)
  - Carnegie Foundation, 5 Mar 1941 (Box 3)
  - "D" (General), Feb-May 1944 (Box 3)
  - Ellsworth, Fred (Alumni Association of the University of Kansas), 1944-1956 (Box 3)
  - Geltch, Mr. and Mrs. Waldemar, May 1944 (Box 3)
  - "H" (General), 6 Feb-18 Apr 1944 (Box 3)
  - "J" (General), Feb 1944 (Box 3)
  - Kidder, E.W., May 1944 (Box 3)
  - "L" (General), Feb-Mar 1944 (Box 3)
  - "M" (General), Feb 1944 (Box 3)
  - Major, Ralph H., Feb 1944 (Box 3)
  - "O" (General), Feb 1944 (Box 3)
  - "R" (General), Feb 1944 (Box 3)
  - Rider, Ruth S., Feb 1944 (Box 3)
  - "S" (General), 1944-1954 (Box 3)
  - Simons, Dolph, 15 Feb-6 Mar 1944 (Box 3)
  - Various (telegrams & excerpts from letters regarding mother's death.), Feb-Mar 1944; n.d. (Box 3)
  - "W" (General), Feb 1944 (Box 3)
  - Wells, Herman B, 7 Feb 1944 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1944-1945 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Family, 1944 (Box 3)